const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Where is the neuropil of the spinal cord most abundant?","answers":[{"option":"Perikarya","bool":false},{"option":"Synapsis","bool":false},{"option":"Gray matter","bool":true},{"option":"Neuroglia","bool":false},{"option":"Unmyelinated axons","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A 30-year-old man reported to the emergency department with a complaint of a dog bite on the right arm. The casualty is conscious but the wound is bleeding. No previous medical or surgical history is reported. After history taking, what is the first step of management?","answers":[{"option":"Administration of anti-rabies immunoglobulin","bool":false},{"option":"Washing and debridement of the wound","bool":true},{"option":"Administration of anti-rabies vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Administration of IV saline","bool":false},{"option":"Testing the dog for rabies","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What does the white matter of the spinal cord consist of?","answers":[{"option":"Perikarya","bool":false},{"option":"Myelinated axon","bool":true},{"option":"Dendrites","bool":false},{"option":"Neuroglia","bool":false},{"option":"Blood vessels","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"The neostriatum consists of which of the following pairs of structures?","answers":[{"option":"Putamen and lentiform nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lentiform and globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen and globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Lentiform and caudate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen and caudate nucleus","bool":true}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"The suprachiasmatic nucleus is responsible for which of the following functions?","answers":[{"option":"Thermoregulation","bool":false},{"option":"Regulation of body's circadian rhythym","bool":true},{"option":"Release of oxytocin","bool":false},{"option":"Release of anti-diuretic hormone (ADH)","bool":false},{"option":"Control of feeding impulses","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following statements refers to red neurons?","answers":[{"option":"Abnormal vacuolization of neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Structural loss along with functional loss of the neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Reactive astrogliosis","bool":false},{"option":"Neurons having bright pink cytoplasm with large nucleus and numerous stout ramifying processes","bool":false},{"option":"Shrinkage of cell body, loss of nissl substance or pyknosis of nucleus","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A 15-year-old boy presents with a fall and fracture of the temporal bone of the skull. On computed tomography (CT) scan, he is found to have an epidural hematoma. What is the most common cause of the hematoma?","answers":[{"option":"Ehlers-Danlos syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Rupture of bridging veins","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Rupture of middle meningeal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Autosomal polycystic kidney disease","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A 29-year-old man steps on a broken bottle with the base of his right foot. His right leg immediately flexes and his left leg extends. What is this reflex called?","answers":[{"option":"Walking reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Stretch reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Patellar reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi tendon reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Crossed extensor reflex","bool":true}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A 50-year-old patient with a history of hypertension is brought to the outpatient department. Examination reveals weakness and loss of sensation mainly affecting right leg, right foot, and perineum. Which one of the following arteries is occluded?","answers":[{"option":"Left middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Right middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Right anterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior cerebral artery","bool":true}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is the corpus striatum a part of?","answers":[{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Limbic system","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":true},{"option":"Reticular formation","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A 79-year-old woman was driving when she had a sudden severe headache. She drove to a service station, stopped the car and slumped over the wheel. She was taken to emergency, where she remained comatose and died 6 hours later. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebral hematoma","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral ischemia","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral edema","bool":false},{"option":"Thromboembolism along with cerebral infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Rupture of berry aneurysm","bool":true}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following is the major part of the limbic system?","answers":[{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Opioid receptor","bool":false},{"option":"Pineal body","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":true}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A child presented to the emergency department with a complaint of a dog bite in the right arm. He was conscious but bleeding from the wound site. The child has completed the EPI vaccination and no significant past medical or surgical history. After documenting the detail of the dog bite, what is the vaccination plan for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Anti-rabies vaccine and appropriate antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-rabies vaccine and usage of immunoglobulin","bool":true},{"option":"Anti-rabies vaccine of both the dog and the child","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-rabies vaccine and cleaning the wound","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-rabies vaccine infiltration into the wound","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A newborn baby was brought to the neurology outpatient department because the large size of the fetal head-MRI shows fluid in the lateral ventricle. The appropriate part of the lateral ventricle formed by the head of the caudate nucleus is?","answers":[{"option":"Superior horn","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior horn","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior horn","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior horn","bool":false},{"option":"Medial horn","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following best defines memory?","answers":[{"option":"Skills of learning","bool":false},{"option":"Ability to store, retain, and recall information","bool":true},{"option":"Genetic control of brain","bool":false},{"option":"Ability to rest ourselves","bool":false},{"option":"Forgetting a movie","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which structure is present superior to the pons and inferior to the thalamus?","answers":[{"option":"Midbrain","bool":true},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral ventricle","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"The molecular layer of the cerebellar cortex does not contain which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Neuroglia","bool":false},{"option":"Parallel fibers of granular cells axons","bool":false},{"option":"Stellate cells","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje cells","bool":true},{"option":"Basket cells","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which is the most safest site for collecting cerebrospinal fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Thoraco lumbar region","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic vertebrae","bool":false},{"option":"Sacro iliac region","bool":false},{"option":"Illiac region","bool":false},{"option":"Lumbar region","bool":true}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is the most inappropriate statement about malformation and developmental diseases of CNS?","answers":[{"option":"May occur due to deficiency of vitamin D","bool":true},{"option":"Many toxic compounds have teratogenic effects","bool":false},{"option":"Mutation of genes that control body patterning","bool":false},{"option":"Aberration of signaling molecules that control body patterning","bool":false},{"option":"Many infectious agents have teratogenic effects","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Myasthenia gravis is primarily a pathology of which structure?","answers":[{"option":"Motor neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Peripheral nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Neuromuscular junction","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"The dura mater does not receive innervation from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"C3","bool":false},{"option":"C1","bool":false},{"option":"C2","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal","bool":false},{"option":"C4","bool":true}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Use of which of the following prevents the occurrence of neural tube defects?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin D","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin C","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin A","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":false},{"option":"Folic acid","bool":true}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is NOT shown by the neuroglial cells?","answers":[{"option":"Capable to divide through life","bool":false},{"option":"Can be best studied with routine staining techniques","bool":true},{"option":"They are non-neuronal cells of CNS","bool":false},{"option":"Arise mostly from neuroectoderm","bool":false},{"option":"They are five to ten times more abundant than neurons","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Neurotransmitters (catecholamines) are mainly derived from which amino acid?","answers":[{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":false},{"option":"Alanine","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":false},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Degeneration of nigrostriatal dopaminergic neurons occurs in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Epilepsy","bool":false},{"option":"Migraine","bool":false},{"option":"Huntington's chorea","bool":false},{"option":"Alzheimer's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Paralysis agitans","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A 36-year-old man fell from a height of 10 feet. As a consequence, he now suffers from incontinence and weakness in the lower limbs. Which of the following statements is correct?","answers":[{"option":"Imaging of dorsal spine should be done","bool":false},{"option":"Imaging of lumbosacral region should be done","bool":true},{"option":"Involvement of cervical spine C4 level","bool":false},{"option":"The middle cerebral artery is involved","bool":false},{"option":"The posterior cerebral artery is involved","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A 25-year-old female had a head injury. She is diagnosed with a case of Kluver Bucy syndrome. Which one of the following signs is not present?","answers":[{"option":"Paralysis of one side of body","bool":true},{"option":"Increased sexuality","bool":false},{"option":"Compulsive tendency to place things in mouth","bool":false},{"option":"Changes in eating behavior","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease emotionality","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Obstruction of the flow of cerebrospinal fluid leads to which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Parkinsonism","bool":false},{"option":"Tumor formation","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocephalus","bool":true}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following regarding oligodendroglia is true?","answers":[{"option":"Can myelinate more than one axon per cell","bool":true},{"option":"Helps in forming pia meningeal layer","bool":false},{"option":"Supporting cells of PNS","bool":false},{"option":"Helps in blood brain barrier formation/maintenance","bool":false},{"option":"Phagocytic cells","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"At what rate does peripheral nerve fiber regenerate?","answers":[{"option":"3 mm/day","bool":true},{"option":"200 mm/day","bool":false},{"option":"0.1 mm/day","bool":false},{"option":"400 mm/day","bool":false},{"option":"100 mm/day","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What hormone is synthesized by the pineal gland?","answers":[{"option":"Melatonin","bool":true},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenaline","bool":false},{"option":"Endorphin","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"The caudate nucleus, putamen, and the globus pallidus collectively make up which structure?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Limbic system","bool":false},{"option":"Basal nuclei","bool":true},{"option":"Reticular formation","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdala","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following features is not present in the Purkinje cells?","answers":[{"option":"Arranged as single row between molecular and granular layer","bool":false},{"option":"Having branching dendrites that ascent at molecular layer","bool":false},{"option":"Largest output neuron of cerebellar cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Can be best studied by routine staining techniques","bool":true},{"option":"Collateral axon that enters the white mater","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is an indolamine derived from tryptophan?","answers":[{"option":"Serotonin","bool":true},{"option":"Chitin","bool":false},{"option":"Prostaglandin","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotriene","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which statement is inappropriate regarding the dorsal horn of the grey matter of the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"It receives and processes sensory inputs","bool":false},{"option":"It is found in all levels of spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"It is less bulky in size than ventral horn of grey matter","bool":false},{"option":"It includes substantia gelatinosa which is homologous to spinal trigeminal nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"It is found in cervical region only","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is wrong regarding the hypothalamus?","answers":[{"option":"Weights around 4gms","bool":false},{"option":"Preoptic area lies infront of hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamic sulcus separates hypothalamus from thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Extends from optic chiasm to mamillary bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior to hypothalamus lies third ventricle","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following histological characteristics is not part of the cerebral cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Contains six layers in all areas of cortex","bool":true},{"option":"Neocortex shows alternate dark and light bands on histological appearance","bool":false},{"option":"Paleocortex is heterogenous","bool":false},{"option":"Isocortex is homogenetically typical","bool":false},{"option":"Archicortex has hetrogenous, three layers","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"REM sleep is characterized by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha waves of EEG","bool":false},{"option":"High voltage, low frequency EEG activity","bool":false},{"option":"70% - 80% of the total sleeping period","bool":false},{"option":"Absence of dreams","bool":false},{"option":"Rapid conjugate movements of the eye balls","bool":true}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Reticular formation nuclei concerned with autonomic regulation of respiration pressure are present in?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral group","bool":true},{"option":"Paramedian group","bool":false},{"option":"Medial group","bool":false},{"option":"Raphe group","bool":false},{"option":"Intermediate group","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which nucleus of the hypothalamus contains the satiety center?","answers":[{"option":"Paraventricular nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Ventromedial nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Supraoptic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Posterolateral nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A 54-year-old man got a head injury during a road traffic accident. He was treated by a neurosurgeon in a tertiary care hospital. On examination, his reflexes are slow, there is a loss of power in the muscles and when he starts movement he feels difficulty turning off his movements. The presenting symptoms present when which one of the following parts of CNS is damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Reticular formation","bool":false},{"option":"Primary motor area of cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":true},{"option":"Pyramid of Medulla oblongata","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Under the morphological classification of the neurons, the bipolar neurons are the ones that bear a single axon and a single dendrite that emerges from the opposite poles of the spindle-shaped body. Which one of the following is an example of a bipolar neuron?","answers":[{"option":"Purkinje cells of the cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal root ganglion of the spinal nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Neurons in the cochlear and vestibular ganglia","bool":true},{"option":"Sensory ganglia of cranial nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Mesencephalic nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Serotonergic innervations of suprachiasmatic nuclei of the hypothalamus involve which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hallucinations","bool":false},{"option":"Deep sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Euphoria","bool":false},{"option":"Circadian rhythm","bool":true},{"option":"Insomnia","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is an autoimmune disease affecting the nicotinic acetylcholine receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Guillain-Barré syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Myasthenia gravis","bool":true},{"option":"Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Duchenne muscular dystrophy (DMD)","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"The lower border of septum pellucidum rests upon the upper border of which structure?","answers":[{"option":"Lentiform nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false},{"option":"Caudate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Fornix","bool":true},{"option":"Internal capsule","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Serotonin or 5-hydroxytryptamine is synthesized from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":true},{"option":"Taurine","bool":false},{"option":"Tri-carboxylic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Tri-acyl glycerol","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following neurotransmitters decreases the pain perception in the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Cellulose","bool":false},{"option":"Substance P","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":true},{"option":"Insulin","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What is the significance of gate control system in pain transmission?","answers":[{"option":"Basis for relief of pain through rubbing","bool":true},{"option":"For release of dopamine from hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"For better pain conduction","bool":false},{"option":"To activate thalamic nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"To increase pain sensation","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Sympathetic stimulation results in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Constriction of blood vessels in the skin","bool":true},{"option":"Puppillary constriction","bool":false},{"option":"Defecation","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased force of heart contraction","bool":false},{"option":"Increased peristalsis","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Contralateral hemiparesis in a patient was attributed to a disorder in the internal capsule. What part of the internal capsule is concerned with related tract?","answers":[{"option":"Genu","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior limb","bool":true},{"option":"Sublentiform part","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior limb","bool":false},{"option":"Retrolenticular part","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which fibers interconnect the two cerebral hemispheres?","answers":[{"option":"Arcuate fasiciculus","bool":false},{"option":"Stria terminalis","bool":false},{"option":"Fornix","bool":true},{"option":"The cingulum","bool":false},{"option":"Geniculo-calcarine tract","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is a voluntary reflex?","answers":[{"option":"Flexion of the arm following a painful stimulus","bool":false},{"option":"Defecation","bool":true},{"option":"Acceleration of the heart","bool":false},{"option":"Salivatory secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Micturition","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following, upon release from the nerve terminal, causes the opening of anionic channels in the postsynaptic neuron?","answers":[{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Nitric oxide","bool":false},{"option":"GABA","bool":true}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which structure in the CNS acts like valves to pour the cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) into the blood?","answers":[{"option":"Choroid plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphatic vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Arachnoid villi","bool":true},{"option":"Tela choroidea","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral arteries","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following is not a feature of a vein of a brain?","answers":[{"option":"Pierce endosteal layer of dura mater","bool":true},{"option":"No valves","bool":false},{"option":"Pierce arachnoid mater","bool":false},{"option":"No muscular tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Lie in subarachnoid space","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A young patient after a motorcycle accident was brought into emergency. After investigations, a diagnosis of fracture of the middle cranial fossa was made. The fractured fossa is not formed by which one of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Petrous part of temporal","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous part of temporal","bool":false},{"option":"Basilar part of occipital","bool":true},{"option":"Greater wing of sphenoid","bool":false},{"option":"Body of sphenoid","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following nerve cell bodies is NOT present in the posterior gray column of the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Phrenic nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Substantia gelatinosa","bool":false},{"option":"Visceral afferent nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus proprius","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus dorsalis","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following elicits inhibitory post synaptic potential?","answers":[{"option":"Calcium influx","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium influx","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium influx","bool":false},{"option":"Chloride influx","bool":true},{"option":"Bicarbonate influx","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"The majority of afferent fibers in basal ganglia come from which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Motor cortex","bool":true},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Associate cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Brain stem","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What does a 'cobweb' appearance of the CSF indicate?","answers":[{"option":"Tuberculous meningitis","bool":true},{"option":"Acute pyogenic meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Viral meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Neurosyphilis","bool":false},{"option":"Viral encephalitis","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What is the most common type of stroke encountered?","answers":[{"option":"Ischemic attack","bool":true},{"option":"Subdural hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Intracerebral hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic type","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhagic attack","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following nerve cell groups do not form a part of the auditory pathway?","answers":[{"option":"Trapezoid body","bool":false},{"option":"Medial geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Superior colliculi","bool":true},{"option":"Cochlear nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Spiral ganglion","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A picture of the cerebrospinal fluid in acute pyogenic meningitis shows which of the following characteristics?","answers":[{"option":"Neutrophils not more than 10,000/cubic mm","bool":false},{"option":"Increased glucose concentration","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Clear fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Increased protein concentration","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which structure is not innervated by the nerve emerging from the groove between pons and medulla?","answers":[{"option":"Buccinator muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Orbicularis oculi","bool":false},{"option":"Sublingual gland","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal gland","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid gland","bool":true}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A 34-year-old man complains of hemisensory loss and hemiparesis of the leg and foot of the contralateral side of the body. He also has difficulty in identifying objects and has developed personality changes. His MRI shows a compromised area with reduced blood supply. Which artery is responsible for these losses?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior spinal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Thermal nociceptors are activated by skin temperature above what value?","answers":[{"option":"20 celsius","bool":false},{"option":"11 celsius","bool":false},{"option":"13 celsius","bool":false},{"option":"45 celsius","bool":true},{"option":"29 celsius","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following tract is concerned with voluntary discrete and skilled movements, especially of distal parts of limbs?","answers":[{"option":"Tectospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Reticulospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Ruberospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Corticospinal tract","bool":true},{"option":"Vestibulospinal tract","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Weber syndrome is caused by the occlusion of a branch of which artery?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Basilar artery","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which cranial nerve motor nuclei are present in the pons?","answers":[{"option":"I and II","bool":false},{"option":"IX, X, and XII","bool":false},{"option":"VIII","bool":false},{"option":"III and IV","bool":false},{"option":"V, VI, and VII","bool":true}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following characterizes upper motor neuron lesions?","answers":[{"option":"Fasiculations","bool":false},{"option":"Disuse atrophy","bool":true},{"option":"Hypoactive muscle stretch reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased muscle tone","bool":false},{"option":"Flaccid paralysis","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is not a feature of meperidine?","answers":[{"option":"It produces mydriasis","bool":false},{"option":"It is a synthetic compound","bool":false},{"option":"It produces miosis","bool":true},{"option":"It has no antitussive effect","bool":false},{"option":"It can cause convulsions in large doses","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following chemical neurotransmitters are present in neurons that have cell bodies in the brainstem projecting to the hypothalamus, limbic system, neocortex, cerebellum, and spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Serotonin","bool":true},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Dopa","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following cranial nerves emerges from the dorsal aspect of the midbrain?","answers":[{"option":"Facial","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear","bool":true},{"option":"Occulomotor","bool":false},{"option":"Abducent","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What is the approximate pH of anaerobically collected cerebrospinal fluid?","answers":[{"option":"7.10","bool":false},{"option":"7.31","bool":true},{"option":"7.15","bool":false},{"option":"7.01","bool":false},{"option":"7.20","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Surgery was planned for a 14-year-old student for his atrial septal defect. On the day of his surgery, he was very anxious. The doctor examined his eyes with an ophthalmoscope and subsequently gave him anxiolytics for his nervousness. Contraction of which of the following eye muscles is the result of the sympathetic effect of anxiety?","answers":[{"option":"Longitudinal muscles causing miosis","bool":false},{"option":"Constrictor pupillae causing miosis","bool":false},{"option":"Dilator pupillae causing miosis","bool":false},{"option":"Dilator pupillae causing mydriasis","bool":true},{"option":"Constrictor pupillae causing mydriasis","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"On ultrasonography, the amniotic fluid around the embryo seems to be in excess. The cavity containing this fluid is lined by cells derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Cytotrophoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Epiblast","bool":true},{"option":"Syncytiotrophoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Extraembryonic mesoderm","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Mr. Arshad, a 45-year-old diabetic man, is referred to the surgical unit for the dressing of a wound on the sole of his left foot. He says that when he took his shoes off at night there was a small stone inside the shoe which had wounded the foot, making it bleed. However, surprisingly, he did not feel pain at all. Conscious perception of this sensation is most likely carried by which one of the following tracts?","answers":[{"option":"Spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column medial lemniscus system","bool":false},{"option":"Corticospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":true}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What is the central metabolite of norepinephrine?","answers":[{"option":"Vanillylmandelic acid (VMA)","bool":true},{"option":"Gamma-aminobutyric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Homovallinic acid (HVA)","bool":false},{"option":"5-Hydroxyindoleacetic acid (5-HIAA)","bool":false},{"option":"3-Methoxy-4-hydroxyphenylglycol (MHPG)","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A 65-year-old man came to the outpatient department. Physical examination revealed that his eyeball deviated laterally because of paralysis of the medial rectus muscle, with the pupil dilated and loss of accommodation. Which structure of the brain is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Mid brain","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"L-DOPA is converted to dopamine by which of the following enzymes?","answers":[{"option":"DOPA hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"DOPA reductase","bool":false},{"option":"DOPA carboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"DOPA oxidase","bool":false},{"option":"DOPA decarboxylase","bool":true}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Damage to the basal ganglia occurs in Parkinson's disease. Which of the following tremors is present in the disease?","answers":[{"option":"Resting tremors","bool":true},{"option":"Flapping tremors","bool":false},{"option":"Intention tremors","bool":false},{"option":"Fine tremors","bool":false},{"option":"Voluntary tremors","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following is the structural precursor molecule of sphingolipids?","answers":[{"option":"Ceramide","bool":true},{"option":"Palmityl CoA","bool":false},{"option":"Cellulose","bool":false},{"option":"Inulin","bool":false},{"option":"Glycerol","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which receptors receive stimuli immediate from external surroundings?","answers":[{"option":"Proprioreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Chemoreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Exteroreceptors","bool":true},{"option":"Enteroreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Teloreceptors","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A 70-year-old man has a 2-day history of a generalized, progressively worsening headache and increasing obtundation. He now complains of stiffness in his neck. On physical examination, vital signs include a temperature of 37°C, a pulse of 85/minute, respiration 23/minute, and blood pressure 130/85 mm Hg. A CBC reveals a WBC count of 16,850/microliter. A lumbar puncture yields cloudy cerebrospinal fluid with raised glucose, decreased protein, cell count of 3800 WBCs (95% polymorphonuclear leukocytes (PMNs) and 5% mononuclear), and 122 RBCs. He receives antibiotic therapy and improves. Which of the following is the most likely long-term complication from this man's current disease?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrocephalus","bool":true},{"option":"Encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Subdural hematoma","bool":false},{"option":"Tonsillar herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellar herniation","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"An 8-month-old baby is brought to the pediatric emergency with a history of high-grade fever, fits, and refusal to take feed. On examination, he has a 102 °F temperature with altered consciousness. On cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) examination, cells are 1200/ml and mostly polymorphonuclear neutrophils. Which type of meningitis is it most likely to be?","answers":[{"option":"Viral meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial meningitis","bool":true},{"option":"Aspetic meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Subacute meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculous meningitis","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"The binding of acetylcholine to its nicotinic receptor increases the permeability of the cell membrane to which one of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Ca++","bool":false},{"option":"K+","bool":false},{"option":"Cl−","bool":false},{"option":"Na+","bool":true},{"option":"Se+","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A 38-year-old patient comes to the outpatient department with the complaint of shaking hands while buttoning clothes, writing, or shaving. The doctor asked him to stand still with his eyes closed and noted a negative Romberg test. Vibration senses are normal in all of the four limbs on examination. Based on the clinical picture, which area is most likely to be damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebral peduncles","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":true},{"option":"Dorsal column","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral horns of spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior limb of internal capsule","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following forms the blood-brain barrier?","answers":[{"option":"Neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth muscle cells","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Osteocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Gracilis and cuneatus tubercles are seen on the surface of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":true},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Mid brain","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Stimulation of the lateral hypothalamus causes an animal to develop which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Fear","bool":false},{"option":"Tranquility","bool":false},{"option":"Rage","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased eating","bool":false},{"option":"Calmness","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"The nuclear bag fibers of muscle spindles are innervated by which of the following sensory afferent fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Aγ fibers","bool":false},{"option":"A𝛿 fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Ia fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Ib fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Aβ fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"The most severe form of cranial neural tube defects (NTD) is characterized by: 1) major portions of the cranium and intracranial structures being absent, 2) orbits and face being present (bulging eyes) 3) polyhydramnios 4) macroglossia 5) very short neck. What type of neural tube defect is this likely to be?","answers":[{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Anencephaly","bool":true},{"option":"Encephalocele","bool":false},{"option":"Acrania","bool":false},{"option":"Iniencephaly","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Hypothalamus releases which of the following substances to induce wakefulness?","answers":[{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenaline","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Orexin","bool":true},{"option":"Muramyl peptide","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A patient comes with a lenticulostriate artery block due to chronic hypertension. Which of the following structures is supplied by it?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior limb of internal capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Whole internal capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior limb of internal capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior limb of internal capsule","bool":true},{"option":"Both anterior and inferior limb of internal capsule","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A child is having a tickling sensation. Which tract would be involved?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal spinothalamic","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic","bool":true},{"option":"Pontomedullary","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinocerebellar","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Damage to which part of the brain results in a condition called athetosis?","answers":[{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Caudate","bool":false},{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":true},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following are the most sensitive cells of the central nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Renshaw cells","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Microglial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Neurons","bool":true},{"option":"Schwann cells","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A patient comes to the neurology department with a complaint of dryness of the mouth and irritation in the eyes. It is diagnosed that there is a lesion in the lacrimal and salivary glands. Which of the nerves is most likely to get affected?","answers":[{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What is the biologically active amine form of phenylalanine?","answers":[{"option":"Valine","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":true},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptamine","bool":false},{"option":"Taurine","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"During lumbar puncture, where is the cerebrospinal fluid withdrawn from?","answers":[{"option":"Ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"Subarachnoid and subdural space","bool":false},{"option":"Central canal","bool":false},{"option":"Subdural space","bool":false},{"option":"Subarachnoid space","bool":true}]},{"id":100,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What is the total volume of cerebrospinal fluid present in the central nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"15 ml","bool":false},{"option":"150 ml","bool":true},{"option":"50 ml","bool":false},{"option":"100 ml","bool":false},{"option":"250 ml","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Electrical recordings from the surface of the head demonstrate that there is continuous electrical activity in the brain which can be recorded in the form of multiple waves. One of these waves is an alpha wave. Which area of the brain does it originate from?","answers":[{"option":"Epithalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamocortical system","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellocortical system","bool":false},{"option":"Pontocerebellar connection system","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A patient comes to the neurology department with a complaint of loss of fine touch in his right upper limb. He is also unable to feel the vibration of his phone. The patient also states that he had a roadside accident a few days back. Which tract is affected?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior spinocerebellar","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior spinocerebellar","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column–medial lemniscus pathway","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following does the vestibulocochlear nerve pass through?","answers":[{"option":"Internal auditory meatus","bool":true},{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen spinosum","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen rotundum","bool":false},{"option":"Jugular foramen","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Absence of alpha waves indicates damage to which tract?","answers":[{"option":"Pontomedullary fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamocortical fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Corticospinal fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A student is studying intracerebellar lesions and wants to find out what nucleus is involved if there is a lesion in the vermis. Which nucleus is involved in this lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Dentate","bool":false},{"option":"Fastigial","bool":true},{"option":"Emboliform","bool":false},{"option":"Clarke","bool":false},{"option":"Globose","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What is the inability to perform alternating movements known as?","answers":[{"option":"Dysdiadochokinesia","bool":true},{"option":"Athetosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hyporeflexia","bool":false},{"option":"Chorea","bool":false},{"option":"Hemiballismus","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Human chorionic gonadotropin (HCG) in a woman's blood indicates pregnancy. It is secreted by which one of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Syncytiotrophoblast","bool":true},{"option":"Placenta","bool":false},{"option":"Epiblast","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Cytotrophoblast","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which structure is present deep in the lateral sulcus?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary motor cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Primary motor cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Primary sensory cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Supplementary motor area","bool":false},{"option":"Insula","bool":true}]},{"id":109,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which nuclei of the hypothalamus are connected to the posterior pituitary gland?","answers":[{"option":"Arcuate and preoptic","bool":false},{"option":"Supraoptic and paraventricular","bool":true},{"option":"ventromedial and paraventricular","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral hypothalamic and ventromedial","bool":false},{"option":"Supraoptic and preoptic","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What does the ventromedial nucleus of the hypothalamus control?","answers":[{"option":"Hunger","bool":false},{"option":"Circadian rhythm","bool":false},{"option":"Water balance","bool":false},{"option":"Temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Satiety","bool":true}]},{"id":111,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Where does the trochlear nerve emerge from?","answers":[{"option":"Superior surface of midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior surface of midbrain","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior surface of midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior surface of midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral surface of midbrain","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following is an inhibitory cell in the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Renshaw cells","bool":true},{"option":"Granule cells","bool":false},{"option":"Amacrine cells","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje cells","bool":false},{"option":"Muller cells","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A 50-year-old patient presents with tuberculous meningitis for the past 10 years. Which of the following is most likely to be his viral history?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatitis C","bool":false},{"option":"Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)","bool":true},{"option":"Herpes simplex virus (HSV)","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis A","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis B","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following receptors detects pressure?","answers":[{"option":"Meissner's corpuscle","bool":false},{"option":"Pacinian corpsule","bool":true},{"option":"Merkel's disc","bool":false},{"option":"Free nerve ending","bool":false},{"option":"Krause end bulb","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Nitric oxide (NO) is one of the neurotransmitters that cause vasodilation. Which of the following is correct regarding nitric oxide?","answers":[{"option":"Catecholamine derivative","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate derivative","bool":false},{"option":"Gaseous neurotransmitter","bool":true},{"option":"Glycine derivative","bool":false},{"option":"Peptide derivative","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A patient presents to the clinic. He is diagnosed with chronic meningitis and has acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS) for the past 14 years. Which organism is the most likely cause for this?","answers":[{"option":"Toxoplasma gondii","bool":false},{"option":"Candida albicans","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium marinum","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium scrofulaceum","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium avium intracellulare","bool":true}]},{"id":117,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the essential amino acids is used to synthesize L-DOPA?","answers":[{"option":"Linolenic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Linoleic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":true},{"option":"Arachidonic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Somatosensory information relays in which nucleus of thalamus?","answers":[{"option":"Mediodorsal nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Ventroposteriolateral nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Ventro lateral nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior nuclear","bool":false},{"option":"Ventro anterior nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A research student is given a task to find out the results of electrical stimulation of different parts of the hypothalamus of a rat. On stimulation of the anterior hypothalamic area and preoptic area, what response is likely to be seen?","answers":[{"option":"Sympathetic response","bool":false},{"option":"Cessation of peristalsis","bool":false},{"option":"Pupillary dilation","bool":false},{"option":"Parasympathetic response","bool":true},{"option":"Elevation of blood pressure","bool":false}]},{"id":120,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following is involved in the anticipation of postural equilibrium?","answers":[{"option":"Primary sensory area","bool":false},{"option":"Spinocerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Premotor area","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibulocerebellum","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebrocerebellum","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is incorrect about the cells of the cerebellar cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Purkinje cells in middle purkinje layer","bool":false},{"option":"Granules cells in inner granular layer","bool":false},{"option":"Basket cell in outer molecular layer","bool":false},{"option":"Stellate cells in granular layer","bool":true},{"option":"Golgi cells in inner granular layer","bool":false}]},{"id":122,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"About the myelin sheath of the peripheral nerve, which of the following is correct?","answers":[{"option":"In the central nervous system, myelinating cells myelinate several internodes of different axons","bool":false},{"option":"It is produced by Schwann cells","bool":true},{"option":"It is produced by oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"It is produced by microglia","bool":false},{"option":"In the peripheral nervous system, myelinating cell myelinate only one internode","bool":false}]},{"id":123,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Regarding myelination in peripheral nervous system, what is the correct statement?","answers":[{"option":"Myelinating fibers have slow conduction velocity","bool":false},{"option":"It is also produced by fibroblasts as well","bool":false},{"option":"It is produced by Schwann cells","bool":true},{"option":"A Schwann cell can myelinate upto 30 axons","bool":false},{"option":"Oligodendrocytes are myelinating cells of peripheral nervous system","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Regarding myelin sheath around axons, what is correct?","answers":[{"option":"Myelin sheath is proportional to the diameter of axon","bool":false},{"option":"Neurons in peripheral nervous system is myelinated by oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Starts developing in fetal life and continues till one year","bool":true},{"option":"Formed by astrocytes in brain","bool":false},{"option":"Nodes of ranvier are not present in CNS","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Where are the cell bodies of postganglionic neurons of parasympathetic fibers located?","answers":[{"option":"Cell bodies in central nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomic ganglia in pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Ganglion in the visceral walls","bool":true},{"option":"Autonomic ganglia in abdomen","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following will not result with stimulation of periventricular and lateral nuclei of the hypothalamus?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Thirst","bool":false},{"option":"Feeling of rage","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased appetite","bool":true},{"option":"Increased appetite","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"About the axons of the peripheral nerve, which of the following is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"It may arise from axon hillock","bool":false},{"option":"It transmits action potential","bool":false},{"option":"It may arise from the perikyon (Soma)","bool":false},{"option":"It may arise from a dendrite","bool":false},{"option":"It contains nissl substance","bool":true}]},{"id":128,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Where does absorption of cerebrospinal fluid occur?","answers":[{"option":"Epidural space","bool":false},{"option":"Arachnoid villi","bool":true},{"option":"3rd ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Aqueduct of Sylvius","bool":false}]},{"id":129,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Damage to which of the following results in lesion of the oculomotor nerve nucleus in the midbrain?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Basilar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral artery","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is an ascending tract in the posterior white column?","answers":[{"option":"Spino-olivary tract","bool":false},{"option":"Fasciculus gracilis tract","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior spinocerebellar tract","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following sensations is detected by nociceptors?","answers":[{"option":"Pain","bool":true},{"option":"Temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Vibration","bool":false},{"option":"Taste","bool":false},{"option":"Pressure","bool":false}]},{"id":132,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which is NOT true about Betz cells?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"They are present in the 6th layer of cerebral cortex","bool":true},{"option":"They are present in the 5th layer of cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Their axons pass to the spinal cord as corticospinal fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Largest cells of the central nervous system","bool":false}]},{"id":133,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Where does the cerebellum receive information concerning muscle movement from?","answers":[{"option":"Caudate","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false},{"option":"Macula","bool":false},{"option":"Proprioceptors","bool":true},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false}]},{"id":134,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What is the rate of formation of cerebrospinal fluid?","answers":[{"option":"100 millilitre/each day","bool":false},{"option":"1000 millilitre/each day","bool":false},{"option":"2000 millilitre/each day","bool":false},{"option":"10 millilitre/each day","bool":false},{"option":"500 millilitre/each day","bool":true}]},{"id":135,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following secretes cerebrospinal fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Dura mater","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Pia mater","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Choroid plexus","bool":true}]},{"id":136,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following tracts starts from the red nucleus, decussates in the midline, and descends down?","answers":[{"option":"Rubrospinal","bool":true},{"option":"Corticospinal","bool":false},{"option":"Tectospinal","bool":false},{"option":"Corticobulbar","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibulospinal","bool":false}]},{"id":137,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is correct for the function of the blood-brain barrier (BBB)?","answers":[{"option":"Provides nourishment and prevents toxic substances from entering the brain","bool":true},{"option":"Allows plasma proteins to enter","bool":false},{"option":"Synthesizes fibroblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Does not maintain a constant environment in the brain","bool":false},{"option":"Allows the big molecules to enter the brain","bool":false}]},{"id":138,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following accurately describes the action of cimetidine on warfarin?","answers":[{"option":"Affects the activity of the platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Increases the metabolism of warfarin","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases the affinity of warfarin for vitamin K epoxide reductase","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases the metabolism of warfarin","bool":true},{"option":"Increases the affinity of warfarin for vitman K epoxide reductase","bool":false}]},{"id":139,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following contains respiratory center in the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":true},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false}]},{"id":140,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Histamine is synthesized from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Methionine","bool":false},{"option":"Proline","bool":false},{"option":"Histidine","bool":true},{"option":"Serine","bool":false},{"option":"Valine","bool":false}]},{"id":141,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Chronic hypertension is the most critical risk factor for developing which of the following types of brain aneurysms?","answers":[{"option":"Traumatic aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Charcot-Bouchard aneurysm","bool":true},{"option":"Sacular aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Dissecting aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Mycotic aneurysm","bool":false}]},{"id":142,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"An 8-year-old boy fractured his skull during his fall. What is the first modality to be used for the examination of the fracture of the skull?","answers":[{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"PET scan","bool":false},{"option":"MRI","bool":false},{"option":"Myelography","bool":false},{"option":"CT scan","bool":true}]},{"id":143,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following cranial nerve nuclei are present in the midbrain?","answers":[{"option":"III and IV","bool":false},{"option":"IV only","bool":false},{"option":"III, IV, and V","bool":true},{"option":"V, VI, and IV","bool":false},{"option":"III only","bool":false}]},{"id":144,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Damage to which one of the following structures of the midbrain produces auditory disturbance?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior colliculi","bool":true},{"option":"Superior colliculi","bool":false},{"option":"Superior brachium","bool":false},{"option":"Medial geniculate body","bool":false}]},{"id":145,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What is dopamine synthesized from?","answers":[{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":true},{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":false},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false}]},{"id":146,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"The extrapyramidal motor system includes the pathway stemming from which of the following points of origin?","answers":[{"option":"Primary motor cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary motor cortex","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Areas 3, 1, and 2","bool":false}]},{"id":147,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following signs and symptom occurs in Wernicke's sensory area lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Inability to read","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to write","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to understand and read only","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to speech","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to understand, read and write","bool":true}]},{"id":148,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What is the rate limiting enzyme in serotonin synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Mono amine oxidase","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptophan hydroxylase","bool":true},{"option":"5-hydroxy tryptophane decarboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Dopa decarboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Aldehyde dehydrogenase","bool":false}]},{"id":149,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What is the function of the vestibular nucleus present in the brainstem?","answers":[{"option":"Muscle spasm","bool":false},{"option":"REM sleep and non-REM sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Antigravity muscles to maintain equilibrium","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory system","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiovascular system","bool":false}]},{"id":150,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What is glycine in the brainstem characterized as?","answers":[{"option":"Amine derivative","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibitory neurotransmitter","bool":true},{"option":"Glycoprotein derivative","bool":false},{"option":"Excitatory neurotransmitter","bool":false},{"option":"Choline derivative","bool":false}]},{"id":151,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following correctly describes the Golgi tendon organs?","answers":[{"option":"Intrafusal fibers contractor","bool":false},{"option":"Neurotransmitters","bool":false},{"option":"Proprioceptors","bool":true},{"option":"Muscle spindles","bool":false},{"option":"Muscle relaxer","bool":false}]},{"id":152,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is not present in the granular cell layer of the cerebellum?","answers":[{"option":"Soma and axons of Golgi cells","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellar glomeruli","bool":false},{"option":"Axons of purkinje cells","bool":false},{"option":"Soma and dendrites of granule cells","bool":false},{"option":"Granule cell axons","bool":true}]},{"id":153,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What is the most likely cause of an increase in proteins in cerebrospinal (CSF)?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperuricemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperglycemia","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglycemia","bool":false},{"option":"Breach in blood brain barrier","bool":true}]},{"id":154,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A patient presents with right-sided hemiplegia and loss of speech. Upon examination, both of his eyes deviate to the left. Damage to which artery can present with these symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior communicating artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior communicating artery","bool":false}]},{"id":155,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following is the histological feature of a peripheral nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Epineurium is a thin, regular collagenous coat","bool":false},{"option":"Around Schwann cells is a thin layer called the perineurium, consisting of reticular fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Each fascicle in invested by collagenous covering called perineurium","bool":true},{"option":"Epineurium does not extend deeply to fill the space between fascicles","bool":false},{"option":"Axons and Schwann cells are not enclosed within layers of connective tissue","bool":false}]},{"id":156,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Histologically, the neurons of the cerebral cortex do not include which of the following cells?","answers":[{"option":"Pyramidal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje cells","bool":true},{"option":"Fusiform cells","bool":false},{"option":"Betz cell","bool":false},{"option":"Granule cell","bool":false}]},{"id":157,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following is the distinguishing feature of the midbrain at the superior colliculus level?","answers":[{"option":"Fourth ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":false},{"option":"Red nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Third ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Third and fourth ventricle","bool":false}]},{"id":158,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Hyperalgesia and allodynia signify which of the following statements?","answers":[{"option":"Tissue repair","bool":false},{"option":"No release of chemicals","bool":false},{"option":"Increased sensitivity of pain","bool":true},{"option":"Release of coagulation factors","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased sensitivity of pain","bool":false}]},{"id":159,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following nerves is not present at the lateral wall of the cavernous sinus?","answers":[{"option":"Ophthalmic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"6th cranial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"3rd cranial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"4th cranial nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":160,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which nucleus is not present on the floor of the fourth ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"7 cranial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"9 cranial nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"6 cranial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"10 cranial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"12 cranial nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":161,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"In bacterial meningitis, compared to normal cerebrospinal fluid, which of the following is found to be typically decreased?","answers":[{"option":"Proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":true},{"option":"Chloride","bool":false}]},{"id":162,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"In lower motor neuron lesions, patient develops which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperesthesia","bool":false},{"option":"Spasticity","bool":false},{"option":"Positive babinski's sign","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperreflexia","bool":false},{"option":"Muscular wasting, hypotonia","bool":true}]},{"id":163,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"The insula lies at the bottom of which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Precentral gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Central sulcus","bool":false},{"option":"Calcarine sulcus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral sulcus","bool":true},{"option":"Parieto-occipital sulcus","bool":false}]},{"id":164,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following key enzymes is required for the synthesis of acetylcholine?","answers":[{"option":"Acetyl cholineaminase","bool":false},{"option":"Choline synthetase","bool":false},{"option":"Choline acyltransferase","bool":false},{"option":"Choline acetyltransferase","bool":true},{"option":"Choline acetylsynthetase","bool":false}]},{"id":165,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Lack of dopamine and degeneration of substantia nigra leads to abnormal movement and is referred to as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Parkinson disease","bool":true},{"option":"Athetosis","bool":false},{"option":"Huntington chorea","bool":false},{"option":"Wilson disease","bool":false},{"option":"Chorea","bool":false}]},{"id":166,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Lesion in cerebellum causes which of the following clinical conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Athermia","bool":false},{"option":"Aphasia","bool":false},{"option":"Aphagia","bool":false},{"option":"Difficulty in balance and gait","bool":true},{"option":"Mental retardation","bool":false}]},{"id":167,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is a  major relay centre for sensory afferents?","answers":[{"option":"Red nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Basal nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":168,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which nucleus of the hypothalamus is involved in the regulation of thirst and hunger?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Ventromedial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Paraventricular nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Supraoptic nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":169,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following does not form the roof of the inferior horn of the lateral ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"Stria terminalis","bool":false},{"option":"Tapetum of corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdala","bool":false},{"option":"Pes hippocampus","bool":true},{"option":"Tail of caudate nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":170,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A 60-year-old elderly male comes to the emergency department while becoming gradually unconscious. Upon conducting magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), there is no clear finding but it is reported by his family that he is fond of eating beef. Creutzfeldt-Jacob disease is suspected. What are the histopathological findings in Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease?","answers":[{"option":"Demyelination","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhagic infarcts","bool":false},{"option":"Granulomas","bool":false},{"option":"Intracytoplasmic vacuoles","bool":true},{"option":"Necrotizing inflammation","bool":false}]},{"id":171,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following statements is not true about the posterior horn of the lateral ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"Superior swelling of medial wall is caused by splenial fibers of corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Medial to tapetum optic radiations are present","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior swelling is produced by calcarine sulcus","bool":false},{"option":"Medial wall has 2 elevations","bool":false},{"option":"Roof and lateral wall formed by tapetum of corpus callosum","bool":false}]},{"id":172,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is responsible for dynamic and static control of muscle spindles?","answers":[{"option":"Withdrawal reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma motor neurons","bool":true},{"option":"Intrafusal nuclear chain","bool":false},{"option":"Beta motor neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha motor neurons","bool":false}]},{"id":173,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A 40-year-old man had an accident. He was initially fine but then started developing behavioral changes after few days. On examination, he had a contusion in the frontal lobe where he hit his head in the airbag. This happened due to?","answers":[{"option":"Excessive bleeding","bool":false},{"option":"Hematoma","bool":false},{"option":"Coup","bool":true},{"option":"Contrecoup","bool":false},{"option":"Fracture","bool":false}]},{"id":174,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is not a derivative of neuroectoderm?","answers":[{"option":"Macroglia","bool":false},{"option":"Microglia","bool":true},{"option":"Ependyma","bool":false},{"option":"Oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":175,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Damping of the motor movements is done by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Reticular system","bool":false},{"option":"Limbic system","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":true}]},{"id":176,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is not a characteristic of midbrain when a transverse section is taken at the level of superior colliculus?","answers":[{"option":"Occulomotor nerve fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Red nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Mesencephalic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":false}]},{"id":177,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is the first choice of modality for diagnosing and examining suspected spinal cord lesions in patients who have suffered trauma?","answers":[{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging","bool":true},{"option":"Computed tomography scan","bool":false},{"option":"Electroencephalography","bool":false},{"option":"Positron emission tomography scan","bool":false}]},{"id":178,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Facial colliculus is formed due to the looping around which of the following nuclei?","answers":[{"option":"Abducens nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Facial motor nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus ambiguous","bool":false},{"option":"Salivatory nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":179,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which nucleus supplies soft palate and pharynx and has fibers from the glossopharyngeal and vagus nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Facial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus ambiguous","bool":true}]},{"id":180,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Fracture of which one of the following can damage facial nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior cranial fossa","bool":true},{"option":"Middle cranial fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cranial fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Jugular Foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Ethmoid bone","bool":false}]},{"id":181,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Before entering the tricarboxylic acid cycle, glucose is metabolized into pyruvate which enters the mitochondria of neurons and glial cells in the form of?","answers":[{"option":"Citrate","bool":false},{"option":"Lactate","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Oxaloacetate","bool":false},{"option":"Acetyl CoA","bool":true}]},{"id":182,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"How many layers are present in the cerebrum and cerebellum respectively?","answers":[{"option":"3 layers, 6 layers","bool":false},{"option":"4 layers, 6 layers","bool":false},{"option":"3 layers, 3 layers","bool":false},{"option":"3 layers, 1 layer","bool":false},{"option":"6 layers, 3 layers","bool":true}]},{"id":183,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is the main function of blood-brain barrier?","answers":[{"option":"Supplies nutrients while preventing hazardous chemicals from reaching the brain","bool":true},{"option":"Provides another layer of cerebrospinal fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Transmits electrical signals between neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Secretes neurotransmitters","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":184,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A patient is suffering from wakefulness and narcolepsy. Which one of the following is affected?","answers":[{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Medial lemniscus","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebelllum","bool":false},{"option":"Reticular formation","bool":true}]},{"id":185,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following innervates intrafusal muscle fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Unmyelinated fibers","bool":false},{"option":"B fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Both alpha and gamma fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma fibers","bool":true}]},{"id":186,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following structures is not part of the sub limbic cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Septal nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Epithalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Amygdala","bool":false}]},{"id":187,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the fibers are used by sensory receptors to carry impulse from the periphery to the central nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Preganglionic","bool":false},{"option":"Postganglionic","bool":false},{"option":"Free nerve endings","bool":false},{"option":"Efferent fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Afferent fibers","bool":true}]},{"id":188,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Pulsatile pain is transmitted through which of the following pathways?","answers":[{"option":"Fasciculus gracilis","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":true},{"option":"Fasciculus cuneatus","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral spinothalamic tract","bool":false}]},{"id":189,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following is the function of ascending reticular system?","answers":[{"option":"Gastrointestinal motility","bool":false},{"option":"Alertness, wakefulness","bool":true},{"option":"Endocrine","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory","bool":false},{"option":"Vasomotor","bool":false}]},{"id":190,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following statements is incorrect about the central sulcus?","answers":[{"option":"Separates frontal lobe from temporal lobe","bool":true},{"option":"Present between two parallel gyri","bool":false},{"option":"Dents the super medial border of brain","bool":false},{"option":"Motor area is in front of the sulcus","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory area is behind the sulcus","bool":false}]},{"id":191,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A boy was pushed down the hill during the fight with his friends. As a result, he acquired a head injury. On examination, a hematoma is seen between the skull base and dura mater. Which of the following arteries is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior meningeal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Internal carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle meningeal artery","bool":true}]},{"id":192,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following is best for the diagnosis of seizures?","answers":[{"option":"Electroencephalogram (EEG)","bool":true},{"option":"Myelography","bool":false},{"option":"Electroencephalogram (EEG) and Electromyography (EMG)","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve conduction","bool":false},{"option":"Electromyography (EMG)","bool":false}]},{"id":193,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following conditions is a neurosurgical emergency?","answers":[{"option":"Subarachnoid hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Subdural hematoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocephalus","bool":false},{"option":"Epidural hematoma","bool":true},{"option":"Intraparenchymal hemorrhage","bool":false}]},{"id":194,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which one of the following bone structures is related to pons?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior clinoid process","bool":false},{"option":"Sella turcica","bool":false},{"option":"Meckel's cave","bool":false},{"option":"Clivus","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior clinoid process","bool":false}]},{"id":195,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Non-REM sleep is most commonly associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Tranquilizers","bool":false},{"option":"Bed wetting","bool":true},{"option":"Nightmares","bool":false},{"option":"Increased systolic blood pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Frequent dreaming","bool":false}]},{"id":196,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Central canal of spinal cord is continuous with:","answers":[{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":false},{"option":"Subarachnoid space","bool":false},{"option":"4th ventricle","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"3rd ventricle","bool":false}]},{"id":197,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"What is the enlargement of the medulla formed by the cortical motor tract?","answers":[{"option":"Trapezoid body","bool":false},{"option":"Olives","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramids","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior olivary nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus cuneatus","bool":false}]},{"id":198,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Using morphine to treat pain may cause following adverse effect:","answers":[{"option":"Addiction","bool":false},{"option":"Miosis","bool":true},{"option":"Increase blood pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Mydriasis","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulation of respiratory centres","bool":false}]},{"id":199,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Axons of the optic nerve are formed by central processes of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Ganglion cells","bool":true},{"option":"Pretectal nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Rods and cons","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar cells","bool":false}]},{"id":200,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Odd statement regarding heparin:","answers":[{"option":"Major side effect is bleeding","bool":false},{"option":"Does not cause bruising","bool":true},{"option":"Activity measured by PTT","bool":false},{"option":"Activity measured by aPTT","bool":false},{"option":"Depends on antithrombin III levels","bool":false}]},{"id":201,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which nerve passes through foramen rotundum?","answers":[{"option":"Lesser petrosal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ophthalmic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":202,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Rhombic alar lips of metencephalon form which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebrum","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":true}]},{"id":203,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"A patient has weakness and difficulty in moving the contralateral lower limb. Which of the following arteries is responsible for this?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cerebral","bool":true},{"option":"Middle cerebral","bool":false},{"option":"Middle meningeal","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cerebral","bool":false}]},{"id":204,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2020","question":"Which of the following is responsible for fine hand movements?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebrum","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Premotor cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Primary motor cortex","bool":true},{"option":"Sensory association centre","bool":false}]}]
export default arr